const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following adverse effects is caused by cimetidine drug?","answers":[{"option":"Bloating","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Alertness","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible gynecomastia","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following amino acids is used for the formation of niacin?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Glutamic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following structures is not found in the porta hepatis?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Portal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic nerve plexus","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following arteries is medial to deep inguinal ring?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior epigastric artery","bool":true},{"option":"Superior epigastric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Iliac artery","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is true about celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Removal of lactose-containing products from diet improves symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal infection by anaerobes is implicated in its pathogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Patients have to avoid gluten containing diet throughout the life","bool":true},{"option":"Gluten is a carbohydrate","bool":false},{"option":"Lamina propria of the small intestine is filled with foamy macrophages","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following forms the medial boundary of the femoral ring?","answers":[{"option":"Pubis symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Pectineus muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Inguinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Lacunar ligament","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following enzymes is deficient in von Gierke disease?","answers":[{"option":"Branching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Debranching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Liver biopsy is taken from which intercostal space?","answers":[{"option":"6-8 intercostal space at mid-clavicular line","bool":false},{"option":"10-12 intercostal space at mid-axillary line","bool":false},{"option":"5-7 intercostal space at mid-axillary line","bool":false},{"option":"8-10 intercostal space at mid-axillary line","bool":true},{"option":"6-8 intercostal space at mid-axillary line","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Hepatitis A virus (HAV) belongs to which class of RNA viruses?","answers":[{"option":"Coronaviruses","bool":false},{"option":"Retroviruses","bool":false},{"option":"Reoviruses","bool":false},{"option":"Picornaviruses","bool":true},{"option":"Flaviviruses","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What is the pH of saliva?","answers":[{"option":"4-5","bool":false},{"option":"6-7","bool":true},{"option":"2-3","bool":false},{"option":"12-15","bool":false},{"option":"10-12","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"In which part of the gastrointestinal tract are submucosal glands present?","answers":[{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenum","bool":true},{"option":"Ileum","bool":false},{"option":"Large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common complication of peptic ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"Perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Diverticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following gives rise to the hepatic artery?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior pancreaticoduodenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac artery","bool":true},{"option":"Splenic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following joins to form the common bile duct?","answers":[{"option":"Cystic duct and common hepatic duct","bool":true},{"option":"Right hepatic duct and cystic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic duct and cystic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left hepatic duct and cystic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Right and left hepatic duct","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"The hexose monophosphate (HMP) shunt occurs in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial matrix","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Cytosol","bool":true},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not supplied by the inferior mesenteric artery?","answers":[{"option":"Sigmoid colon","bool":false},{"option":"Distal one-third of transverse colon","bool":false},{"option":"Anal canal above anal valve","bool":false},{"option":"Anal canal below anal valve","bool":true},{"option":"Lower part of the descending colon","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"In which of the following diseases is the lower esophageal sphincter (LES) defective?","answers":[{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn disease","bool":false},{"option":"Achalasia","bool":true},{"option":"Hirschsprung disease","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following diseases has impaired gastrointestinal motility?","answers":[{"option":"Gastroparesis","bool":true},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory bowel disease","bool":false},{"option":"Dumping syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following represents Peyer's patches?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse lymph nodes in gastrointestinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes aggregates in duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoid aggregates in large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoid aggregates in ileum","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic fatigue","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Malabsorption","bool":false},{"option":"Bloating","bool":false},{"option":"Colectomy","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What does the presence of hepatitis B surface antibodies in routine blood tests indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Past infection and vaccination to hepatitis B","bool":true},{"option":"Past infection only","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"No vaccination to hepatitis B","bool":false},{"option":"No successful recovery from the infection","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following causes acute pancreatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol and liver injury","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity and gall stones","bool":false},{"option":"Colectomy and liver injury","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol and gallstones","bool":true},{"option":"All of them","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following can be assessed through X-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve compression","bool":false},{"option":"Torn ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following does not form the boundary of the caudate lobe of the liver?","answers":[{"option":"Fissure for the ligamentum venosum","bool":false},{"option":"Fissure for ligamentum teres","bool":true},{"option":"Fissure for the inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Porta hepatis","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following causes cancer in peptic ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"Gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Dumping syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":true},{"option":"Duodenal compression","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not correct for the stages of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits respiratory center","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxes pharyngoesophageal sphincter","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit gastroesophageal sphincter","bool":true},{"option":"Relaxes gastroesophageal sphincter","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is crossed by the root of the mesentery of the small intestine?","answers":[{"option":"3rd part of duodenum","bool":true},{"option":"Right psoas minor muscle","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of duodenum","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is true for the morphology of Barrett's esophagus?","answers":[{"option":"Velvety red patches","bool":true},{"option":"Cuboidal esophageal epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"No mucous vacuoles","bool":false},{"option":"One type of mucosa with no alternates","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following enzymes is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which part of the salivary glands secretes saliva?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Salivary ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliated cells","bool":false},{"option":"Acini","bool":true},{"option":"Granules","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most accurate test for Helicobacter pylori infection?","answers":[{"option":"Stool antigen test","bool":false},{"option":"Urea breath test (UBT)","bool":true},{"option":"Urine culture","bool":false},{"option":"Radioactive iodine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which muscle is originated by the lateral part of the inguinal ligament?","answers":[{"option":"Cremaster muscle","bool":false},{"option":"External oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Transversus abdominis","bool":true},{"option":"Rectus abdominis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following involves the aspect of healthcare that deals with the communication of patient care, diagnosis, management, and drugs between doctors and patients?","answers":[{"option":"Transpersonal care","bool":false},{"option":"Holistic care","bool":false},{"option":"Management continuity","bool":false},{"option":"Informational continuity","bool":true},{"option":"Relational continuity","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is correct about hernias?","answers":[{"option":"Direct inguinal hernia is not covered by external spermatic fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect inguinal hernias are medial to inferior epigastric vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral hernia protrude above inguinal ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Epigastric hernia is present between xiphisternum and umbilicus","bool":true},{"option":"Diaphragmatic hernia in infants is most commonly due to hiatal hernia","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"How many net ATPs are produced as a result of the citric acid cycle?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"10","bool":false},{"option":"12","bool":true},{"option":"6","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following cancers is associated with helicobacter pylori?","answers":[{"option":"Gallbladder cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue (MALT) lymphoma","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following antacid is responsible for causing metabolic or systemic alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aluminium hydroxide","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium carbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium hydroxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following statements is inappropriate about the stomach and intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Enteroendocrine cells present throughout the length of the small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal (oxyntic) cells present throughout deeper parts of the gland","bool":false},{"option":"M (microfold) cells overlying the lymphoid follicles of Peyer patches","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous neck cells present in the deeper parts of gastric glands","bool":true},{"option":"Paneth cells are present in the depths of intestinal glands","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following arteries supplies the gallbladder?","answers":[{"option":"Pancreaticoduodenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Splenic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior mesenteric artery","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is correct for the lysosomal storage diseases?","answers":[{"option":"It occurs due to increased enzyme concentration","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs due to decrease in enzyme function","bool":true},{"option":"It occurs due to decreased lysosomes production","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs due to increased lysosomes production","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs due to increased product degradation","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of chronic gastritis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following enzymes digests proteins in the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Pepsin","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleosidase","bool":false},{"option":"Trypsin","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What is the mode of transmission of familial hypercholesterolemia?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":true},{"option":"Mitochondrial disease","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for the digestion of carbohydrates in the duodenum?","answers":[{"option":"Endopeptides","bool":false},{"option":"Salivary amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic amylase","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreatic lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Exopeptides","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following enzymes is responsible for digesting protein in the duodenum?","answers":[{"option":"Pepsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Trypsin","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following does not compensate for the weakness of the anterior abdominal wall?","answers":[{"option":"Transversus abdominis covering the superficial ring","bool":true},{"option":"Splitting of superficial fascia below the umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"Arching lower fibers of internal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Reinforcement of anterior wall by origin of internal oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique pathway of inguinal canal","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"A good ethical doctor should have which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Justice","bool":false},{"option":"Nonmaleficence","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a product of the uronic acid pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Glucuronate","bool":true},{"option":"NAD and NADPH","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"UDP glucose dehydrogenase","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following does not supply blood to the pancreas?","answers":[{"option":"Gastroduodenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior inferior pancreaticoduodenal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Great pancreatic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior inferior pancreaticoduodenal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Where does the inferior vena cava drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Common iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Lumbar veins","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What do the superior mesenteric and splenic veins combine to form?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic portal vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior mesenteric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Colic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following statements regarding venous drainage is correct?","answers":[{"option":"The splenic vein drains into the inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Blood from the kidneys do not directly drain into the hepatic portal vein","bool":true},{"option":"The right renal vein is longer than the left renal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Blood from the right colic vein directly drains into the hepatic portal vein","bool":false},{"option":"The hepatic veins do not drain in the inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following structures is the right kidney not related to anteriorly?","answers":[{"option":"Descending part of the duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic flexure of colon","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Section of small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Right colic flexure","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"A slim, 40-year-old mother of 5 children presents to the clinic with a subcutaneous swelling in the groin. Upon examination, it is found that she has a hernia and should opt for surgical repair. Which of the following is the most likely hernia in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect inguinal hernia","bool":true},{"option":"Umbilical hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Incisional hernia","bool":false},{"option":"Direct inguinal hernia","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"A patient presents to the clinic with complaints of dark urine and clay-colored stools. Upon physical examination, scleral icterus and yellowing of the skin are observed. Which of the following would most likely be the cause of the given symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Hemochromatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Reye syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Cholelithiasis","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"A 25-year-old adult presented to a clinic with symptoms of jaundice. Blood analysis showed that the amount of conjugated bilirubin equaled 0.6 mg/dL and unconjugated bilirubin equaled 0.9 mg/dL. What is the total bilirubin in 1 dL of his blood?","answers":[{"option":"0.9 mg/dL.","bool":false},{"option":"0.6 mg/dL","bool":false},{"option":"1.5 mg/dL","bool":true},{"option":"0.3 mg/dL","bool":false},{"option":"0 mg/dL","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following conditions is responsible for pathologically high levels of unconjugated bilirubin in a newborn's blood?","answers":[{"option":"Annular pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Physiologic jaundice of the newborn","bool":false},{"option":"Dubin-Johnson syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Biliary tract obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Crigler-Najjar syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Physiologic jaundice of the newborn occurs due to which of the following","answers":[{"option":"Low glucose consumption","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of gut bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Temporarily low glucuronyl transferase activity","bool":true},{"option":"Transiently low glycuronyl hydroxylase activity","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of uridine diphosphate-glucuronosyltransferase (UGT)","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following serves as the medium for the measurement of bilirubin in serum?","answers":[{"option":"Diazotized sulfanilic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Distilled water","bool":false},{"option":"Brine","bool":false},{"option":"Paraffin wax","bool":false},{"option":"Agar jelly","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What step of the citric acid cycle involves substrate-level phosphorylation?","answers":[{"option":"Succinate to fumarate","bool":false},{"option":"Succinyl-CoA to succinate","bool":true},{"option":"Fumarate to malate","bool":false},{"option":"Citrate to isocitrate","bool":false},{"option":"Oxaloacetate to citrate","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a common complication of celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"B-cell neoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes insipidus","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatosplenomegaly","bool":false},{"option":"Central pontine myelinolysis","bool":false},{"option":"T-cell lymphoma","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following can be used to make glucose via gluconeogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"Lysine","bool":false},{"option":"Leucine","bool":false},{"option":"Palmitic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Propionate","bool":true},{"option":"Even chain fatty acids","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the given cell types cannot oxidize fatty acids?","answers":[{"option":"Myocytes","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":true},{"option":"Adipocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with portal hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Caput medusae","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal varices","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites","bool":false},{"option":"Jaundice","bool":true},{"option":"Congestive splenomegaly","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following, when functioning appropriately, can serve as the strongest, personal and social support system?","answers":[{"option":"Acquaintances","bool":false},{"option":"Video games","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital staff","bool":false},{"option":"Professors","bool":false},{"option":"Family","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which one of the following is detrimental in raising kind and well-behaving children?","answers":[{"option":"Teaching them how to respect other living things","bool":false},{"option":"Serving as a good role model","bool":false},{"option":"Having no set rules at home","bool":true},{"option":"Ensuring they recieve a good education","bool":false},{"option":"Making yourself accessible to them","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Hyperlipidemia is most likely to be found in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Tropical sprue","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":true},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Abetalipoproteinemia","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following enzymes is responsible for cleaving off glucose-1-phosphate from the peripheral end of a long branch of glycogen during glycogenolysis?","answers":[{"option":"Glycogen phosphorylase","bool":true},{"option":"Debranching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Branching enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which disease and its causative enzyme deficiency is incorrectly paired?","answers":[{"option":"Von Gierke disease - glucose-6-phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"McArdle disease - muscle glycogen phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Hers disease - liver glycogen phosphorylase","bool":false},{"option":"Cori disease - branching enzyme","bool":true},{"option":"Pompe disease - lysosomal-α-1,4-glucosidase","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by a pathogen that invades the small intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Hirshprung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Oral candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Whipple disease","bool":true},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Where in the small bowel is the myenteric plexus located?","answers":[{"option":"On the tips of villi in the lumen","bool":false},{"option":"Inside the lacteals, connected to the lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Between the lamina propria and serosa","bool":false},{"option":"In the submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Between the inner circular and outer longitudinal muscle layers","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Where in the gastrointestinal tract is Auerbach's plexus located?","answers":[{"option":"In the microvilli","bool":false},{"option":"In the lamina propria","bool":false},{"option":"In the muscularis externa","bool":true},{"option":"In the mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"In the serosa","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a part of the gastrointestinal tract wall?","answers":[{"option":"Submucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Lumen","bool":true},{"option":"Muscularis propria","bool":false},{"option":"Serosa","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a feature of ulcerative colitis?","answers":[{"option":"Creeping fat","bool":false},{"option":"Skip lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Cobblestone mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Broad-based ulcers","bool":true},{"option":"Fissures","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of these amino acids does not participate in transamination?","answers":[{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Serine","bool":false},{"option":"Arginine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Lysine","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"The ilioinguinal nerve passes through what structure in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal ring","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial inguinal ring","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse colon","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral sheath","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Under normal conditions, the gallbladder can hold up to what quantity of bile?","answers":[{"option":"7 ml","bool":false},{"option":"50 ml","bool":true},{"option":"0 ml","bool":false},{"option":"450 ml","bool":false},{"option":"600 ml","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What do parietal cells secrete?","answers":[{"option":"HCl and intrinsic factor","bool":true},{"option":"HCl and HCO₃⁻","bool":false},{"option":"Somatostatin and somatomedin","bool":false},{"option":"Water and sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrin and secretin","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a rate-limiting enzyme of fatty acid synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Acetaldehyde dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acyl-CoA synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl-CoA carboxylase","bool":true},{"option":"Transketolase","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"At what level does the inferior vena caval hiatus lie?","answers":[{"option":"T10","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":true},{"option":"T12","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What structure is affected when the inferior rectal vessels are damaged?","answers":[{"option":"External anal sphincter","bool":true},{"option":"Descending colon","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid colon","bool":false},{"option":"Vulva","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Where are the haustra found?","answers":[{"option":"Oral cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Large intestine","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following does not contain plicae circulares?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum","bool":false},{"option":"Jejunum","bool":false},{"option":"Large intestine","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is true regarding bile canaliculi?","answers":[{"option":"They empty into bile ductules","bool":false},{"option":"They are the largest branches of the biliary tree","bool":false},{"option":"They only contain unconjugated bilirubin","bool":false},{"option":"They are found in the gall bladder","bool":false},{"option":"They arise from the intercellular spaces between hepatocytes","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a major cause of celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Intussusception","bool":false},{"option":"Gliadin peptides","bool":true},{"option":"Aldolase B deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Tropheryma whippelii","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which enzyme activates trypsinogen?","answers":[{"option":"Enterokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombin","bool":false},{"option":"Amylase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Trypsinogenase","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following activates most other gastrointestinal enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Trypsinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Trypsin","bool":true},{"option":"Phosphofructokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Catalase","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the only neutral gastrointestinal secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Pancreatic juice","bool":false},{"option":"Bile","bool":false},{"option":"Urine","bool":false},{"option":"Saliva","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric juice","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What does the enteric nervous system do?","answers":[{"option":"Controls GI secretion and motility","bool":true},{"option":"Controls voluntary movements","bool":false},{"option":"Links GIT to heart","bool":false},{"option":"Controls gut bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Provides pain sensation","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a cause of coronary artery disease?","answers":[{"option":"Stress","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty diet","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol consumption","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Exercise","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What function do villi in the large intestine play?","answers":[{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of enzymes","bool":false},{"option":"Exocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Absorption of materials","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is not assessed in a lipid profile?","answers":[{"option":"High-density lipoprotein (HDL)","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoprotein lipase","bool":true},{"option":"Triglycerides","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Low-density lipoprotein (LDL)","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What can be used to test for non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH)?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose tolerance test","bool":false},{"option":"Chvostek's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function test","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Urine test","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"The levels of which of the following enzymes predominantly increase during liver failure?","answers":[{"option":"Alanine aminotransferase","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine aminotransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Enterokinase","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following compounds is commonly used as a radiocontrast dye?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium iodide","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrooxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Methylene blue","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Barium sulphate","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Upon swallowing, what movement does the larynx show?","answers":[{"option":"Does not move","bool":false},{"option":"Upward and anteriorly","bool":true},{"option":"Upward and posteriorly","bool":false},{"option":"Downward and posteriorly","bool":false},{"option":"Downward and anteriorly","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which of the following is true regarding gastroesophageal reflux disease?","answers":[{"option":"The esophagus shows a bird beak sign on X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Contents from the esophagus move down into the stomach","bool":false},{"option":"The stomach undergoes intestinal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"The stomach shrinks","bool":false},{"option":"Contents from the stomach move up into the esophagus","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"What is the situation called when a person is rejected and ostracized by almost all of his/her friends and family?","answers":[{"option":"Break up","bool":false},{"option":"Annoyance","bool":false},{"option":"Social rejection","bool":true},{"option":"War","bool":false},{"option":"Quarantine","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/gastrointestinal/2017","question":"Which vein does not directly drain into the portal vein?","answers":[{"option":"Splenic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior pancreaticoduodenal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Left gastric vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior pancreaticoduodenal vein","bool":true},{"option":"Superior mesenteric vein","bool":false}]}]
export default arr